Mounif Haydar 30th June, 1991 Mobile: +961 71 432116

E-mail:mounifhaydar@gmail.com

https://mounifhaydar.github.io

Objectives

As a certified computer engineer from the Islamic University of Lebanon with 10 years of experience in software development, I am currently serving as a Senior Software Developer and Leadership Mentor at NEXtCARE - Allianz Partners. I look forward to embracing a new challenge using my experience, knowledge, and leadership skills to contribute to the growth of your esteemed institution.

Professional Experience

Automated Engine for Adjudication – Jan 2018 – Present

Developing modules in an Automation Engine to adjudicate requests submitted from Hospitals to Insurance companies. Automating 80% of the requests to be routed without human intervention, covering more than 10 countries and handling at least 500,000 transactions per day.

Leading a team to migrate solutions from legacy technologies to modern platforms and microservices, integrating with CI/CD DevOps pipelines.

Providing Technical Guidance: Developed an auto-detection solution for bugs that compares legacy and new system responses, alerting on discrepancies.

Mentoring and Supporting junior developers, fostering professional growth, assigning tasks, and reviewing code.

Mobile Application – July 2016 – Jan 2018

Developed mobile applications using the Cordova framework and Webservice in .NET framework. **Full Stack for Mobile and Web Applications:** Enhanced UI/UX practices, Managed app bundle/APK generation.

Skills: Java Spring Boot, JPA, REST API, MVC, Angular, JUnit Test, JSON Web Tokens (JWT), EHCache, Gradle, Jenkins, Docker, Grafana, Nexus, Drools, JMeter, Cordova, ONSEN UI, NodeJS, npm, Git, Linux, PL/SQL, PostgreSQL, and Oracle Database.

Software Developer | Cedar IT Services

September 2014 – July 2016

Developed a web application for banking system. Migrating the CDR (Central de Risk) application of the BDL (Bank du Liban) using JSF framework.

Developed and delivered an efficient and reusable code, optimized screen responsivity, and configured database servers, Bonobo, Git, and WebSphere on Linux environments.

Skills: JavaEE, JSF, ICEfaces, Hibernate, Spring, Maven, WebSphere, Bootstrap, Oracle Database, IBM DB2.

Personal Projects

Websites based on ASP.NET framework (C#/VB.net):

- o apapapark.com
- o gis-developers.com
- o Online Computer Sales Project: Developed an ASP.NET website enabling users to search for computers and compare PCs, and place orders.

Java Desktop Application:

- o Student Registration Program
- o Classroom Booking Program

Education

Computer and Communication Engineering (CCE) - Islamic University of Lebanon

Aug. 2014

<u>Thesis:</u> Prepaid Electric Meter - Integrated software and hardware components. Developed an **Android app** for payment transactions and designed an electronic circuit to monitor consumption and communicate via NFC. (.NET Web Services and SQL Server database).

Lebanese Baccalaureate II –SV - Hussein Ali Nasser High School

Aug. 2009

Certifications:

CISCO CCNA Exploration LAN Switching and Wireless CISCO CCNA Exploration Routing Protocols and Concepts CISCO CCNA Exploration Network Fundamentals

October 2013 March 2013 October 2012

Languages

Other Skills

- Management and Communication Skills: Experienced in Agile methodology and Sprint planning, with a proven track record of leading a team for the last 6 years.
- **Technical Skills:** Interest and experience in designing Electronics circuits, Robotics and Home Automation. Developed smart home devices for personal use. Also I have wide knowledge in the following work-related technical skills:
 - o Workflow and Reporting: JPBM, TIBCO Jaspersoft (Java Reporting)
 - o **DevOps and Containerization:** experienced in Jenkins and Docker.
 - o Web Development: JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, REST API, CSS3, HTML5, .NET Core
 - o **Development Tools:** Eclipse, VisulaStudio, XCode.
 - o Version Control Systems: GIT, SVN, VSS (Microsoft Visual SourceSafe)
 - o **Analytics Tools:** Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager for tracking and data analysis.
 - o **Database Management and Scripting:** PL/SQL, Oracle databases, DB2, MySQL, PostgreSQL, focusing on procedures, functions, triggers, and jobs.
- **Self-learner:** I try to keep myself updated with the latest technologies. I invest my time browsing through various lectures on the Web Code Geeks and websites such as javacodegeeks.com, cordova.apache.org and linkedIn/learning.